Guide to the J. Mayone Stycos papers,1955-2004.
Stycos, J. Mayone papers, 1955-2004.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
J. Mayone Stycos papers, 1955-2004.
21-33-3171.
J. Mayone Stycos.
3 seven drawer filing cabinets, and 16.3 cubic feet
Correspondence, clippings, articles, photographs, reports, brochures, syllabi, notes, teaching materials, diary notes, reviews, speeches, bulletins, memoranda.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Personal and professional papers and biographical information about Professor Stycos, sociologist, photographer and professor of sociology.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Joseph Mayone Stycos received a B.A. from Princeton University and a Ph.D. from Columbia University. After serving as one of the first Population Council Fellows (1954-55), he came to Cornell in 1957. In 1962, he founded the International Population Program, which he directed until 1992. He also served as Professor of Sociology, and chair of the Department of Sociology and Anthropology (1966-1970), as director of the Latin American Studies Program (1962-1966) and as Professor of Rural Sociology (1988- ). He has authored numerous books and articles on population issues including birth control, fertility, socio-psychological dimensions in husband-wife relations, adolescence, survey research, and population and the environment. Most of his work focused on Latin America, but he also gave attention to Egypt, India, China, Poland, Turkey, and the U.S. Throughout his career, he was an avid photographer, and illustrated a number of his books with photographs taken during the course of his research, including a book of photographs, entitled Children of the Barriada and one entitled Margin of Life, on which he collaborated with Cornell Capa.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Stycos photograph collection includes photos from around the world on a wide range of subjects, plants, people buildings. Includes photographs of China, focusing on images relating to population control programs, taken in 1989. Many photos of Central America, India, Europe, and Upstate New York. Includes photographs of China, focusing on images relating to population control programs, taken in 1989. Also, biographical information about Professor Stycos, correspondence, articles, annual reports, department files, and course material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Stycos, J. Mayone.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Dept. of Rural Sociology.
Subjects:
Birth control--China.; Family size--China.; Communication in birth control--China.
Places:
China.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Photographs
Boxes 1-9, 12, 15-33, Mapcase
Series II. Correspondence, Publications, Subject Files, and Speeches
Boxes 10-14, Magnetic Tape Recording
Series III. Biographical Information
Box 12
Series IV. Newspaper Clippings
Series V. Grants and Programs
Box 14
Series VI. Audio and Film
Box 32
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Photographs
  Items in Boxes 1-9 are framed.
  - Two Shanghai girls, 6 (Box 1)
  - Little painter, 8 (Box 1)
  - Two old ladies in front of Bao Guang Monastery, Sichuan, 15 (Box 1)
  - A monk sweeping, 16 (Box 2)
  - Young men on tractor, Sichuan, 17 (Box 2)
  - Family planning worker with pie charts, 19 (Box 2)
  - Two old men with flag, 27 (Box 3)
  - Posing in front of lotus flower, 28 (Box 3)
  - Old man with bag, 29 (Box 3)
  - Old man in straw hat, 30 (Box 4)
  - Children washing hands in kindergarten, 36 (Box 4)
  - Eating ice cream, 37 (Box 4)
  - Old man with cane, 38 (Box 5)
  - Two family planning officials, 41 (Box 5)
  - Poco Loco taking photo, 42 (Box 5)
  - Family planning poster, Chengdu, 9 (Box 6)
  - One-child family sculpture, Guangdong, 10 (Box 6)
  - Poco Loco, 11 (Box 6)
  - Little girl playing piano, 13 (Box 7)
  - Reflection on buildings, Chengdu, 14 (Box 7)
  - Performance in Kindergarten, 20 (Box 7)
  - Little boys near the Summer Palace, 21 (Box 8)
  - Old women selling votive candles, 22 (Box 8)
  - Lehigh Valley Train and Building, None (Box 8)
  - Family Planning Worker w/Charts, 12 (Box 9)
  - Grand-parents and child, 43 (Box 9)
  - Publications featuring Stycos photographs, Various (Box 12, Folder 19)
    Various publications, about, authored by, or featuring Stycos photographs. Includes several publications about Latin America.
  - Publications from the exhibition of Stycos photos (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Additional indices to Stycos photograph albums (Box 12, Folder 21)
    Also includes some Photoshopped photos and pictures from Storm King N.Y..
  - Notes and articles on Photoshop (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Slides (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - CAPA/JMS L.A. slides box (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous slides box (Box 12)
  - Matted photos (Box 15)
    Mixed photos, matted 11x13, various locations.
  - Signs of Latin America photo box (Box 15)
    Various sizes, matted and loose.
  - Photo album St. Lucia 2007 (Box 16)
  - Unlabeled photo album (Box 16)
    Includes photo of Stycos
  - Loose photos (Box 16)
    Mostly 11 x 14 prints, many featuring plants.
  - Loose photos in open box (Box 16)
    Box says black and white seconds and Central American Faces, but contains color and black and white items of various subjects.
  - Photo album I (Box 16)
    Index at front. 11 x 14, black and white, largely from the 1970s. Locations include: Lansing N.Y., Brighton England, Twin Glens woods Ithaca, Peru, Port of Spain Trinidad, Digby Nova Scotia, Brazil, Mexico City, Senegal, others.
  - Photo album II (Box 16)
    Index at front. 11 x 14, black and white. Locations include: Twin Glens Ithaca, pipes, JFK airport, Treman Park, Buenos Aires, New Paltz, Saugerties, Geneva N.Y., Bogota Columbia, Tegucigalpa, Digby Nova Scotia, others.
  - Photo album III (Box 16)
    Index at front. 11 x 14, black and white. Locations include: Copper canyon, Eiffel Tower Paris France, Lehigh Valley train, Central New York, England, Dunedin Florida, Digby Nova Scotia, Freeville N.Y., Aruba, Cornell Plantations, Mexico, Buenos Aires, others.
  - Photo album IV (Box 16)
    Index at front. 11 x 14, color. Locations include: Peru, Havana Cuba, River Po, Guatemala, Twin Glens Ithaca, Sapsucker Woods, Danube River Austria, Merida Mexico, Florida, Cornell, Tappan Zee Bridge New York, Aurora, and others.
  - Photo album V (Box 16)
    Index at front. 11 x 14, color. Locations include: Washington D.C., Spain, Malta, Oxaca Mexico, Merida, Mexico City, Twin Glens Ithaca, Cayuga Lake, Cuba, Danube River Austria, others.
  - Photo album VI (Box 17)
    Index at front. 11 x 14, mainly black and white, some color. Locations include: Warsaw Poland, Venice Italy, Tompkins County, Costa Rica, Maryland, Buenos Aires Argentina, Geneva Switzerland,Twin Glens Ithaca, Ottawa Canada, Florida, Cornell Plantations, Libe Slope Cornell, Lansing New York,, Digby Canada, Peru, England, others.
  - Photo album VII (Box 17)
    Index at front. 11 x 14, color. Locations include: Twin Glens Ithaca, Merida Mexico, Malta, Provence France, Copper canyon, Lake Titicaca, Rome Italy, Havana Cuba, Sapsucker Woods, Poland, London England, others.
  - Photo album VIII (Box 19)
    Index at front. 13 x 19, color. Locations include: Sapsucker Woods, Copper Canyon, Cornell Plantations, Danube Austria, Upstate New York, Merida, New Tate Museum, Tompkins County, Lucerne Switzerland, Clifford, New York, Gore Island Senegal. Also a photo of Maria Stycos and one of Sid Vicious graffiti
  - Photo album IX (Box 33)
    Index at front. 11 x 17, black and white and color. Locations include: New York State, Zocalo, Mexico City, Nature, Copper Canyon, Tompkins County, Cuba, Hotel Tequendama Columbia, Jamaica Inn Florida, Saugerties New York, and others.
  - Photo album X (Box 16)
    Index at front. 11 x 14, black and white and color. Locations include: Honduras, Aurora, Syracuse, Freeville, Ithaca, New York, Mexico City, Digby Canada, Warsaw, El Salvador others.
  - Photo album XI (Box 27)
    Index at front. 11 x 14, various. Album appears to have been disassembled as it is mostly empty.
  - Matted large format photos (Box 18)
    Mostly 13 x 19 photos.
  - Loose and matted photos (Box 19)
    Mostly 13 x 19 or larger prints. Includes photo of Maria Stycos and son.
  - Matted photos (Box 20)
    Mostly 13 x 19 or larger black and white prints.
  - Matted photos (Box 21)
    Mostly 13 x 19 or larger color prints. Matted for exhibition or sale.
  - Mounted photos (Box 22)
    Mostly 18 x 20, mostly color. Many mounted to foam board for exhibition.
  - Mounted photos (Box 23)
    Mostly 18 x 20, black and white. Many mounted to foam board for exhibition. Includes exhibit text.
  - Matted and loose photos (Box 24)
    Mostly 11 x 14, various subjects.
  - Misc. album, red (Box 25)
    8 x 10, color. Index at front. Locations include: Geneva Switzerland, Cuba, Mexico, Warren Hall Cornell, Copper Canyon, Sapsucker Woods, others. Incldues photo of Stycos' shadow, also one of Maria Stycos and son, and a photo of planes from a plane.
  - Flora album, red (Box 25)
    Mostly 8 x 10, color photos of plants.
  - Surreal and Spanish Graffiti album (Box 25)
    Mostly 8 x 10.
  - High Quality album A (Box 25)
    Mostly 8 x 10, various subjects.
  - High Quality album B (Box 25)
  - Unlabeled album, blue (Box 25)
    Mostly 8 x 10, various subjects, many experimental and Photoshopped photos.
  - Exhibits album (Box 25)
    Folder of material removed from a binder regarding exhibitions of Stycos photographs.
  - China exhibition photos and negatives (Box 25)
    Photo box of correspondence, contact sheets, and negatives of Chinese photographs
  - Miscellaneous sleeved photographs (Box 25)
  - Matted small photos (Box 25)
    Small matted photos, mostly of manipulated or abstract imagery.
  - Envelope of small loose photos (Box 25)
    Small photos. Includes photo of Maria Stycos with father opera singer Marian Nowakowski in a car, also a photo J. Stycos grandfather, and a self portrait of Stycos and wife Maria.
  - Troy album (Box 26)
    Troy, N.Y. photos. Includes photos of cemeteries and of the Troy District Shirt Factory.
  - Joseph album (Box 26)
    Many self portraits or photographs of Joseph and family
  - Stays album (Box 26)
    Includes Mexico, Paraguay, Latin America, Peru, Bolivia
  - London album (Box 26)
  - Unlabeled blue album (Box 26)
    Nautre, plants and animal photos.
  - Mexico album (Box 26)
  - Lviv Ukraine, Storm King New York, Mexico, Provence France, album (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous album (Box 27)
    Mostly photos of landscapes and nature.
  - Black and White Digital album (Box 27)
    Includes 1948 self-portrait that has been Photoshopped.
  - Abstracts album (Box 27)
  - Block Island, Everglades, Sciencenter, Ithaca album (Box 27)
    Photos of Block
  - Miscellaneous, Erie Canal album (Box 27)
  - Matted photos (Box 28)
    Mostly 11 x 14, color, black and white, various subjects. Includes photo of Maria Stycos.
  - Abstract, Miscellaneous album (Box 29)
  - Walls and Windows Los Angeles album (Box 29)
  - Signs of Latin America album (Box 29)
  - Puerto Rico, Dominican Republic album (Box 29)
  - Clinics, Barriadas album (Box 29)
  - Brazil, Paraguay, Argentina album (Box 29)
  - Brazil Oleg family negatives album (Box 29)
  - Dr. Wilcox Tarrow FLA, Honduras, Peru. negatives album (Box 29)
  - 1975 contact sheets box (Box 30)
  - Slide box, surreal, Spanish graffiti, others (Box 30)
  - Poland album (Box 30)
  - Canada album (Box 30)
  - China album (Box 30)
  - Egypt, India, Africa album (Box 30)
  - Copper Canyon, Danube album (Box 30)
  - Family album (Box 31)
  - Family album (Box 31)
  - Family album (Box 31)
  - Family album, green (Box 31)
  - Maria album (Box 31)
  - Marek album (Box 31)
  - Baby album (Box 31)
  - Family ca. 1975 album (Box 31)
    Negatives and contact sheets
  - Early negatives album (Box 31)
    Includes various landscapes, Bates College graduation photos in front of Coram Library
  - Family album "A" (Box 32)
    Mainly photos of Maria and Marek
  - Family album "B" (Box 32)
    Mainly photos of Christina and Steven
  - Family album "C" (Box 32)
    Mainly photos of Marek
  - Family album "D" (Box 32)
  - Family album "E" (Box 32)
  - Family album "F" (Box 32)
    Mainly photos of Stycos
  - Slides and film box (Box 32)
    Includes Barriadas, many others. 8mm film boxes, films have been transferred to larger reels.
  - Duplicates & Seconds, 11x17 (Box 33)
  - Extras, 13 x 19 (Box 33)
  - Matted photos, Barriada contact sheets and negatives (Box 34)
    Medium format, 11 x 13, some used for exhibition at Kendal October 2016, plus Barrida material.
  - Matted photos (Box 35)
    Large sizes, 18 x 20, some used for exhibition at Kendal October 2016.
  - Very large format photographs (Map-case Y-19)
    Black and white, various subjects.
  - Posters featuring Stycos photographs (Map-case Y-19)
    Cornell Population and Development Program, Retrospective Glimpse Exhibit
- Series II. Correspondence, Publications, Subject Files, and Speeches
  - Rural Sociology - Move from College of Arts and Sciences to Agriculture - Correspondence, 1982-1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Rural Sociology - Move from College of Arts and Sciences to Agriculture, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Rural Sociology - Move from College of Arts and Sciences to Agriculture, 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Rural Sociology - Move from College of Arts and Sciences to Agriculture, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1963-1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1963-1988 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Stycos (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Briefing on Central America Population Resource Center, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Harvard University - Center for Population Studies - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - University of Pennsylvania - Population Studies Center - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Florida State University Correspondence, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Muskingum College Correspondence, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Sterilization Conference in Santo Domingo, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Sweden Trip, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - IPP Annual Report, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Annual Report Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Annual Report, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Annual Report, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Annual Report, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Annual Report for Sociology, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Annual Report, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Annual Report, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Annual Report - Correspondence, 1968-1968 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - IPP Annual Report, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - Fulbright, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence as Chair of Sociology, 1966-1970 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence as Chair of Sociology, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence; Certificate, 1959-1992 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - IPP Grants and Contact Information, 1982-1989 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - PDP Geneva-on-the-Lake Workshop, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Activities Reports, 1995-2000 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Graduate Students Information, 1985-1990 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Graduate Students Information, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Brochures, 1963-1995 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Course Syllabi, 1980-1997 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Rural Sociology 201 Quizzes/Handouts, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Diary Notes; Trip Reports, 1963-1973 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Diary Notes, 1962-1966 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Diary Notes; Diary Index, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Diary Notes - Colombia, Guatemala, etc., 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Diary Notes - Jamaica, Chile, Puerto Rico, etc., 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Book Reviews, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Documents and Speeches from Retirement Celebration, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence and Information Re: Appointments, 1966-1995 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence and Information Re: Appointments, 1957-1965 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Articles and Bulletins, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Memoranda; Correspondence; Faculty Evaluations, 1986-1994 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - PDP Program Activities, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - PDP Program Activities, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - PDP Program Activities, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - IPP Annual Reports, 1982-1986 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - PDP Working Papers Series, 1996-2002 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - PDP Working Papers Series, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - International Population Program Reports, 1973-1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Articles by Stycos - A, 1967-1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Articles by Stycos - B, 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Articles by Stycos - C, 1949-1967 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Articles by Stycos - D, 1966-1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Articles by Stycos - E, 1963-1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Articles by Stycos - F, 1951-1971 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Articles by Stycos - G and H, 1955-1974 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Articles by Stycos - I and L, 1964-1974 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Articles by Stycos - M and N, 1957-1975 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Articles by Stycos - O, 1962-1969 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Articles by Stycos- P, 1947-1977 (Box 11, Folder 12-16)
  - Articles by Stycos - R and S, 1960-1974 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Articles by Stycos - S, 1948-1971 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Articles by Stycos - T and U, 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Articles by Stycos - U and Z, 1954-1974 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper articles, 1967-1969 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Latin American Press Survey - Set of codebooks, newspaper codes, 1965-1968 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Latin American Press Survey - Documentation, 1965-1968 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Latin American Press Survey - Analysis, 1965-1968 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Latin American Press Survey - Analysis, 1965-1968 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Latin American Press Survey - Reports - Book #4, 1965-1968 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    Including "Latin American Newspaper Coverage of Population & Family Planning", July 1967 - August 2968
  - Birth Control Articles from Puerto Rico News, 1950s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Margin of Life" - photograph exhibiton, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
  - Book Reviews, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - International Population Program - Reprint series, 1962-1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Early papers by Stycos, 1940s (Box 12, Folder 12)
    Includes work from Princeton and others. Titles include: And Yet a Little While, Mud on the Wall, On Love, On Science and Religion, The Negro Problem Prejudice and Discrimination, Excerpts from a Novel to Be, and others.
  - "Unfinished Masterpieces", 1940s (Box 12, Folder 13)
    From a folder with the above title. Contains papers by Stycos including some done at Princeton. Titles include, Mysticism a Short Critique, A Psychologist Looks at Latins, And Yet A Little While, Howard,
  - Lecture Notes, 1940s (Box 12, Folder 14)
    Typed notes possibly from sociology classes attended by Stycos at Princeton.
  - Publications by Stycos from Columbia University, 1949, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Includes A Conceptual Analysis of Motivation In Men's clothing Behavior October 1949 and Changes in Razor Blade Brands A Study of Consumer Motivations April 1950
  - 1950s Correspondence and Publications, 1950s (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Includes letter form the U.S. Ambassador to Haiti, Ernest Bonhomme, about doing research in Haiti. Also a publication titled The Survey Under Unusual Conditions, The Jamaica Human Fertility Investigation by Kurt W. Back and J. Mayone Stycos.
  - Greece Files, 1960s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Articles, correspondence, and publications about Greece and Greeks. Includes paper titled Cyprus and the Greco-Turkish Conflict by Steven Stycos, Greek Immigration, Greeks of Ithaca,
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1960s-1970s (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Includes stationary for Stycos Cleaners, various letters, and notes.
  - Publications featuring Stycos photographs, Various (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - JMS Papers, 1974-2002 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - JMS Articles Part I, 1964-2000 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - JMS Articles Part II, 1964-2000 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - JMS Papers, 1994-1998 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - JMS Articles Part I, 1958-1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - JMS Articles Part II, 1958-1998 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - GOES (Global Omnibus Environmental Survey), 1993-1997 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - GOES (Global Omnibus Environmental Survey), 1979-1996 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - GOES Workshop (Oslo, Norway), 1994 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - JMS Sabbatic/ General, 1977-1994 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - JMS Articles, 1989-1993 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - JMS Consultantship File, 1977-1993 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - INDIA, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Publications, 1974-1990 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - United Nations Population Division (Costa Rica paper), Oct.-Dec. 1982 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - JMS Consultantship-Ford Foundation, Oct. 1977 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - JMS Speeches-Programas y Estrategias de Informacion y Educacion en Planificacion Familiar en America Latina, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Speeches, 1965-1976 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Books (reviewed by JMS) (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - JMS-Vitae, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Published Reviews of Books by Stycos and Reviews by Stycos of Various Population Books, 1955-1965 (Box 14, Folder 78)
  - Manuscripts (comments on) Reviews by JMS: Part I (Box 14, Folder 79)
  - Manuscripts (comments on) Reviews by JMS: Part II (Box 14, Folder 80)
  - Magnetic Tape Recording: VOA (Voice of America) Broadcast JMS "Population and Family Planning Programs in Newly Developing Countries", 1963 (Box 14)
  - Photocopy of Kiana, 1966 (Box 32)
    Greek
- Series III. Biographical Information
  - Who's Who in the East (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Who's Who in the World and in America (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Who's Who in America - Marquis Who's Who, inc. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - American Men and Women of Science - The Jaques Cattell Press (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Transcripts from Princeton and Columbia University (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Series IV. Newspaper Clippings
  - Filed Newspaper Clippings, 1964-1969
    Three seven drawer filing cabinets contain clippings from various Latin American newspapers concerning population issues including the 1968 Encyclical Humanae Vitae. The clippings are filed by country and then chronologically
- Series V. Grants and Programs
  - Population Multi-Media Exhibit (Proposal to NSF), 2004 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Haitises Proposal Packard Fnd. (Not Funded), 1998 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Hartell Gallery: Exhibit China Photographs, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Academic Approval for "Attitudes, Values, and Expectations of Colombian Adolescents", 1988 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence From Rockefeller Foundation Re: "Attitudes, Values, and Expectations of Colombian Adolescents", 1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Academic Approval for "A Survey on Population Knowledge and Attitudes of School Children in China", 1988 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Pre-Proposal for "Aging, Adolescence, and The One-Child Family in China", 1988 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Academic Approval for "A Population Education Feasability Study in China", 1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Peru Proposal, Spanish Version, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Academic Approval for "A Peruvian National Survey on Population/Sexuality Knowledge and Attitudes of School Adolescents", 1987 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Proposal sent to Roger Guerra Garcia Re: Peruvian Proposal, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Program Proposal for "A Peruvian National Survey on Population/Sexuality Knowledge and Attitudes of School Adolescents", 1987 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Notice of Grant Award for "Modernization, Modernity, and Psycho-Demographic Change", Apr. 14, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 14)